FARAZ HASHMI

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

CONTACT 519-808-3393 fhashmi.canada@gmail.com www.fhashmi.pro London, Ontario, Canada SKILLS Machine Learning Computer Vision

MS SQL Server, IBM DB2, MySQL

Natural Language Processing

Containerize using Docker

Python, C#, Angular

AWS CI CD using Github actions

ML Flow Tracking

Apache Spark

Team coordination and leadership

EDUCATION

Master of Science in

Machine Learning and Al

Liverpool John Moore's University

2020-2022

Ranked#1 for Top Performers awards and secured GPA 4/4.

Bachelor of Engineering in

Electronics and Communications

Rajeev Gandhi Technical University

2016-2018

Received honors degree by securing 79%

PROFILE

Machine learning engineer having 4 years of experience in developing end to end Al applications. Before Al, worked as a senior .NET developer for 13 years specializing in full stack application development.

Work experience across diverse geographies and cultures including India, USA and Canada. Highly praised by every client throughout these years with key strengths being technical adaptability and work ethics.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Analyst - Software Engineering

DXC Technology - Canada

2022-2024

- Developed a proprietary small business insurance product that brought \$25M in earned premium till date.
- Designed and developed a machine learning based model to identify an auto insurance claim being fraud or not. Libraries used -NumPy, Pandas, PyYAML, Python_Box, SciKitLearn, imblearn, Flask.
 The model is live and is referred by claim adjusters.
- Designed and developed a computer vision based model to look at accidental car images and identify and estimate the damage. Libraries used -NumPy, PyYAML, Python_Box, Pillow, TensorFlow
 Model needs updates with requirements to access damage on a video.
- Designed and developed a Large Language Model (LLM) to summarize the
 declarations page of an insurance document. Also, developed similar model to
 summarize state insurance forms. Libraries used PyTorch, ensure, HuggingFace transformers, BERT base NER, rouge_score
 NER identifies person, address, coverages, limits and premiums.
 Summarizer summarizes long forms and declaration document.
- Tracked all model experiments using MLFlow.
- · Deployed models and created AWS CI CD pipelines.

Professional Application Engineer

DXC Technology - USA

2014-2022

- Worked with several clients for development of various enterprise applications in insurance domain.
- Developed various POCs for use of Al in insurance domain (like chatbot, customer churn predictor).
- Developed excellent relationship with customer based on exceptional performance which helped bring more contracts to the company.

FARAZ HASHMI

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

CERTIFICATIONS

- Associate in Insurance The Institutes - USA
- Microsoft Certified Application
 Developer
 Microsoft India

ACHIEVEMENTS

Won Employee of the Quarter award

Won Property and Casualty gems award

Several 'Key to Success' awards

Captain of cricket team in DXC tournament

LANGUAGES

Hindi

WORK EXPERIENCE

Some individual projects to mention

Self Development

2020-2024

- Designed and developed a Machine Learning Framework that trains several ML models on a subset of data and picks up the best model based on given configurable metric.
- The identified best model is then trained on full dataset. It utilizes the regularization and cross-validation techniques to result in a generalized model.
- All the hyperparameters are also configurable and so fine tuning can be performed once a model is finalized.
- Modular programing was done to support easier maintenance and it also makes use of MLFlow to track experiments.
- This framework supports both classification and regression and so has proven to be great to perform quick POCs.

Senior Software Developer

DXC Technology - India

2009-2014

- Design .NET core MVC applications.
- Gather requirements from client, design, code, test, and perform retrospective in an agile environment, delivering results in two-week sprints.
- Design and architect a framework to house next generation web applications.
 This framework was so versatile, that team members can just plug and play web apps to it.
- Analyze Systems for complex performance issues and work on improving performance.
- Subject Matter Expert (SME) on DXC's proprietary insurance product 'Exceed'.
- Share technical expertise with team members by mentoring them in weekly sessions.

Software Engineer

Tech Mahindra - India

2007-2009

- Understand and analyze the technical specifications and suggest code optimization ideas.
- Develop software code as per specifications.
- Ensure error free product delivery to client.